Nina Rapak

Horsham, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Nina-Rapak/a54e8d1d65d9c3f9

SOFTWARE SYSTEMS ENGINEER/ANALYST-Active Top Secret/Polygraph

IT project manager with broad experience in the software project life cycle starting with requirements analysis, software architecture and design, software development in C and software/systems testing. Focus on configuration management and quality assurance of the software product including production of all related documentation insuring a quality release of the software product. Performed extensive customer interaction including formal presentations and contract acquisition.

Proficient in the following software, technical and business applications:

- Requirement Analysis
- Release Coordination
- Engineering/Program Management
- Software Configuration Management
- Administration
- Product Documentation (Word, Visio)
- Customer Relations

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Engineer

AMETEK, Inc. - Harleysville, PA - 2014 to 2016

Responsibilities

A350 Electrical Heater Controller Program

- Software team lead responsible for the delivery of embedded software to the customer following the project processes which are based upon DO-178B and company defined processes
- Communicate directly with customer to ensure requirements are being satisfied, issues are evaluated and resolved using DOORS requirements database tool
- Responsible for reporting of project metrics to project management
- Generate project deliverables using established software tools
- Support development of solutions to problems in conjunction with hardware and systems groups
- Coordinate software development with an off-shore development and test team using configuration management using PVCS and issue tracking tool Mantis
- Perform Software Quality Assurance functions as needed for delivery of work products.

Associate

Thomas J Rapak CPA - Elkins Park, PA - 2013 to 2014

Support general operations of the accounting office. Duties include data entry, payroll tax compliance and bank reconciliation. Responsible for set up of all client documentation for the new tax year.

Engineering Team Lead

DHPC Technologies, Inc - Woodbridge, NJ - 2011 to 2013

Integrated Aircraft Survivability Equipment Technology Demonstration Program (IASE TDP)

- Managed the software development team through the software development process following CMMI and customer specific process guidelines using configuration management and issue tracking tools (Plastic, JIRA)
- Ensured the developed C code for the real-time data collection system satisfied the software requirements via extensive code reviews.
- Employed Object Oriented concepts to the analysis and design phases
- Planned the schedules and tasking for design, implementation and testing.
- Presented project design to the customer in design review milestones.
- Defined the set of tests for the software build prior to delivery to the customer.
- Developed the project documentation for the requirements, design, and implementation.
- Developed testing scenarios and documentation for integration and systems testing.
- Managed the requirements database using a requirements tracking tool (DOORS)
- Quality Assurance Team Lead responsible for definition of company Quality Plan

Associate

Drexel University - Philadelphia, PA - 2011 to 2011

Provided support in implementation of the Drexel University Mechanical Engineering Department website using

Sitecore web Content Management System.

Lead Member Engineering Staff

L-3 Communications Systems - East - Camden, NJ - 1981 to 2009

Camden, New Jersey 1981 - 2009

Formerly Lockheed Martin, Martin Marietta, GE Aerospace, and RCA

Lead Member Engineering Staff

- Responsible for day-to-day management of software teams of up to 10 people resulting in improved software process compliance, administration and cost account management.
- Interfaced extensively with the customer in defining the requirements design and implementation to ensure a quality product.
- Provided requirements management and traceability using requirements tracking tools (DOORS)
- Effectively supported the project Technical Director to insure customer requests were properly incorporated in the delivered product.
- Member of the SEI CMM Level 3 Compliance Project with responsibility for: defining L-3 processes, developing Organizational Software Process Improvement Plan, Conducting Peer Review courses as well as ensuring projects are adhering to the process.
- Generated and maintained metrics on progress against the schedule and budget
- Developed the plan and the budget using the Earned Value Management reporting with MS Project.
- Developed real-time embedded software using C on both Linux and Windows platforms,
- Developed applications in C and Ada on Linux and Windows platforms.
- Engaged in the integration testing lead role in planning, defining and executing software tests and coordinating software releases for testing.
- Completed general project support activities including documentation generation, peer reviews and Software change control board evaluation of problem reports.
- Generated the required documentation such as Product Specification, User Guide, Software Development Plan, Software Configuration Management Plan and Quality Assurance Plan.
- Presented the Preliminary and Detailed design to the customer at required customer milestones.
- Developed build procedures and coordinated execution of various security processes to facilitate delivery of releases to various classified sites.
- Focused projects on a rigorous implementation of the configuration management of the developed code as well as tracking all issues during testing using ClearCase and ClearQuest tools.

CORPORATE SOFTWARE/SYSTEMS TRAINING

- EVMS and CMMI Level 3 process requirements
- CS-E Organizational Training courses
- CS-E Effective Team Leadership Training
- C Programmer course
- CS-E Information Assurance Certification courses CprE-530 and CprE-532
- NTU Embedded Software Development
- Telelogic DOORS training
- Rhapsody OOA/OOD and TOOL training
- Introduction to CMM, Fundamentals of GPS, ISDN technology and application
- Cryptography Security and Privacy

EDUCATION

Certificate in Program Management

Pennsylvania State University 2011

BS in Mathematics

Pennsylvania State University 1981